Guide to the Records of the Leo Baeck Institute London undated, 1907-2008 (bulk 1956-2000) AR 6682
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series I: Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, undated, 1930s-2000; bulk 1956-2000; 11.5 linear feet and one oversize item.
  - Subseries 5: Unpublished materials, undated, 1930s-1983; bulk 1960s; 1.2 linear feet.
    - Freeden, Herbert "Salomon Maimon", undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "Der Glaube des Paulus", undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Goldhammer "Adolf Boehm", 1960 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Gurewicz, Paul "Kultur-historisches Museum ueber das Leben der Juden…", 1964? (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Heilbrunn, Rudolf "J. Dreyfus und Co., Frankfurt a.M. / Berlin", 1961 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Hildesheim "Education in Israel", undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Hirshler, E.E. "The Jews in Germany", undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Jacobson, Jacob "Juedische Trauungen in Berlin", 1957 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Jashuvi, Josef "Die juedische Schule in Deutschland", undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Laqueur, Walter "The Jewish Question", 1961? (Box 11, Folder 44)
      Photographs
    - Liebeschuetz, Hans "Problems and Aspects of Diaspora History in 19th-century Germany", undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Meisel, Joseph "A Blessed Memory: The Center of Jewish Culture in Berlin", 1959-1965 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Schwab, Hermann "My Life", 1960? (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Sommer, Bruno "The Trial of the Century", 1962? (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sommer, Bruno "The Trial of the Century", undated, 1930s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Strauss, Heinrich, "Juedisches Kunstschaffen -- ein Minoritaetenproblem", undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Strauss, Heinrich, "Schicksal und Form des Tempelleuchters der Makkabaerkoenige", undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Tramer, H. "Objektivitaet und Werturteil", 1961 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wehle, Kurt "A History of Czechoslovak Jews", undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weinryb, Bernard, "Enlightenment and German-Jewish 'Haskalah'", 1960 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series II: Schriftenreihe, 1959-1994; 0.5 linear feet.
  This series concerns the Schriftenreihe wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Instituts, an ongoing series of monographs on German-Jewish history published by LBI London. The first subseries contains three correspondence files for publications from the 1960s, primarily containing author-editor correspondence. No files for the approximately 70 other Schriftenreihe publications are found in this collection. The second subseries consists primarily of clipped reviews of the Schriftenreihe publications.
  A complete list of Schriftenreihe publications is found at LBI London's website.
  This series was divided into two subseries.
  - Subseries 1: Publication files, 1965-1969; 3 folders.
    This subseries contains three correspondence files for publications from the 1960s, primarily containing author-editor correspondence. No files for the approximately 70 other Schriftenreihe publications are found in this collection.
    This series is arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Fischer, Staat und Heer, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Liebeschuetz, Das Judentum, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Liebeschuetz, Von Simmel zu Rosenzweig, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2: Reviews, 1959-1994; 0.4 linear feet.
    This subseries consists of reviews of the Schriftenreihe from European, American, and Jewish publications. In addition to off-prints, clippings, and typed copies, some folders also contain index cards that reference other reviews. The last folder contains promotional fliers prepared by the publisher.
    This subseries is arranged by Schriftenreihe number. The folder titles consist of the author's last name and the first few words of the publication's title. The last folder consists of the publisher's promotional fliers.
    - 1. Adler-Rudel, Ostjuden in Deutschland, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 2. Simon, Aufbau im Untergang, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 3. Susman, Die geistige Gestalt, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 4. Kisch, Schriften zur Geschichte, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - 5. Turnowsky-Pinner, Die zweite Generation, 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 6. Kohn, Kraus - Schnitzler - Weininger, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 7. & 8. Stern, Der preussische Staat, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 9. Kahler, Die Philosophie Brochs, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 10. Homeyer, Deutsche Juden als Bibliophilen, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 11. Glatzer, Zunz, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - 12. Freeden, Jüdisches Theater in Nazideutschland, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - 13. Mosse, Entscheidungsjahr, 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - 13. Mosse, Entscheidungsjahr, 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - 14. Reissner, Eduard Gans, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - 15. Toury, Politische Orientierungen, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - 16. Wilhelm, Wissenschaft des Judentums, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - 17. Liebeschuetz, Judentum im deutschen Geschichtsbild, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - 18. Kestenberg-Gladstein, Neuere Geschichte der Juden, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - 19. Hamburger, Juden im oeffentlichen Leben, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - 20. Fischer, Judentum, Staat und Heer, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - 21. Belke, Lazarus - Steinthal, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - 23. Liebeschütz, Von Simmel zu Rosenzweig, 1970-1974 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - 24. Stern, Der preussiche Staat, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - 25. Mosse, Deutsches Judentum im Krieg, 1971-1977 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - 27. Lichtenstein, Juden von Danzig, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - 28. Richarz, Der Eintritt der Juden, 1974-1977 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - 29. Adler-Rudel, Juedische Selbsthilfe, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - 33. Mosse, Juden im Wilhelminischen Deutschland, 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - 35. Liebeschuetz, Das Judentum in der deutschen Umwelt, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - 39. Mosse, Revolution and Evolution, 1981-1988 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - 45. Paucker, Juden im nationalsozialistischen Deutschland, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - 48. Mosse, Second Chance, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - 49. Heid, Juden und Deutsche Arbeiterbewegung, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Promotional fliers, 1959-1976, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 43)
- Series III: Administrative, undated, 1951-1996; 9 linear feet.
  This series contains materials related to the general functioning of LBI London. Most of the series consists of general correspondence and correspondence between LBI's centers in London, New York, and Jerusalem. Such internal reports and meeting minutes as were found are in subseries 3, but this is most likely an incomplete collection of organizational documents.Subseries 4 contains a few miscellaneous folders and documents.
  Each subseries has a date range that is more restrictive than the series range. There are also large temporal gaps in some subseries, which are noted below.
  This series is divided into four subseries, by document type and function.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, undated, 1951-1996; 7 linear feet.
    This subseries contains general and topical correspondence.
    The general section contains correspondence such as inquiries, invitations, death notices, and meeting and travel arrangements. Topics include LBI and the yearbook, Jewish history, other Jewish heritage organizations, office issues, the occasional clipping or unsolicited manuscript attached to a letter, research requests, and personal correspondence from friends of LBI London.
    Note that there are gaps from 1970-1977 and 1991-1994 in the general section.
    The topical section contains folders created by LBI London for correspondence about certain subjects. They are primarily from the early days of the organization, and include correspondence with board members and other organizations.
    This subseries is arranged into two sections, general and topical. The general folders are arranged chronologically. Within a particular year, the folders follow the original arrangement, alphabetically by correspondent. The topical folders follow the original folder titles, and are arranged alphabetically.
    - General, 1956-1969; 1978-1996
      - A, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - B, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - C-I, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - J-N, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - O-S, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - T-Z, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - A-D, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - E-L, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - M-S, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - T-Z, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - A-I, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - J-R, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - S-Z, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - A-H, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - I-S, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - T-Z, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - A-K, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - L-S, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - T-Z, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - A-J, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - K-S, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - T-Z, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - A-J, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - K-S, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - T-Z, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - A-G, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - H-P, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - R-Z, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - A-D, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - E-K, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - L-R, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - S-Z, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - A-C, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - D-G, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - H-K, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - L-O, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - P-S, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - T-Z, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - A-B, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - C-F, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - G-H, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - I-K, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - L-N, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - O-S, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - T-Z, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - A-F, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - G-H, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - I-L, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - M-R, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - S-Z, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - A-E, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - F-J, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - K-O, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - P-Z, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - A-C, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - D-G, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - H-K, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - L-P, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - R-S, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - T-Z, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - A-G, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - H-S, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - T-Z, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - A-H, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - I-M, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - N-Y, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - A-G, 1980 August - 1981 September (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - H-N, 1980 August - 1981 September (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - P-Z, 1980 August - 1981 September (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - A-L, 1981 October - 1983 July (Box 17, Folder 1)
        During previous processing, this folder became disorganized.
      - M-Z, 1981 October - 1983 July (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - A-B, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - C-E, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - F-G, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - H-I, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - J-M, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - N-S, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - T-Z, 1983 August - 1986 July (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - A-E, 1986 August - 1987 July (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - F-K, 1986 August - 1987 July (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - L-R, 1986 August - 1987 July (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - S-Z, 1986 August - 1987 July (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - A-F, 1987 August - 1989 July (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - G-L, 1987 August - 1989 July (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - M-Z, 1987 August - 1989 July (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - A-F, 1989 August - 1990 July (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - G-L, 1989 August - 1990 July (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - M-S, 1989 August - 1990 July (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - T-Z, 1989 August - 1990 July (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - A-G, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - H-K, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - L-N, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - R-Z, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - A-F, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - G-M, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - N-R, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - S-Z, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Topical, undated, 1951-1979; bulk 1956-1959
      - Bach, Hans, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Board Member Circulars, 1956-1962 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Board Member Correspondence, A-L, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Board Member Correspondence, L-S, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Board Member: Altmann, 1956-1959 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Board Member: Jacobson, 1956-1959 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Board Member: Liebeschuetz, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Board Member: Liebeschuetz, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Board Member: Lowenthal, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Board Member: Reichmann, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Board Member: Rosenbaum, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Board Member: Schmidt, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Board Member: Wiener, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Board Member: Wilhelm, 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Chodkiewicz, Count Leopold, 1967-1979 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Council of Jews from Germany, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Council of Jews from Germany, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Council of Jews from Germany, 1957-1959 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Frankfurt Jews Project, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Gesellschaft der Freunde des LBI, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Israel (Board), 1958 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Israel (Board) A, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Israel (Board) B-Z, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - J.C.B. Mohr, 1957-1965 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Leo Baeck Charitable Trust, 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Leo Baeck Memorial Book A-K, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Leo Baeck Memorial Book L-W, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Liebeschuetz, Hans, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Liebeschuetz, Hans, 1960-1966 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Liebeschuetz, Hans, Undated, 1967-1977 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Office correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Office correspondence, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Office correspondence, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Tramer, Hans, 1958-1962 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Translation, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Weltsch (General), 1954-1957 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Weltsch (General), 1951-1972 (Box 24, Folder 52)
      - Weltsch (70th Birthday), 1961 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Wirtschaftsforschung, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: LBI Correspondence, 1955-1994; bulk 1977-1994; 1.6 linear feet.
    This subseries contains correspondence between LBI's London, New York, and Israeli centers. In addition to mundane organizational correspondence, topics include discussions about the intended focus of the LBI as an institution. This subseries also contains some minutes of LBI London and LBI International boards.
    Note that in the LBI New York section, there is a gap between 1956 and 1977.
    The LBI center in Israel is located in Jerusalem. The folders marked LBI Tel Aviv contain correspondence with academics at University of Tel Aviv. It is unlikely they were ever considered a separate branch, but the folders were left as found.
    The folders were separated into New York and Israeli sections, but otherwise left as maintained. Each section is arranged chronologically.
    - LBI New York, 1955-1994; bulk 1977-1994
      - LBI NY A-Z, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - LBI NY General, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - LBI NY Gruenewald, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - LBI NY Jerusalem, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - LBI NY General, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - LBI NY General, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - LBI NY General, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - LBI NY A-Z, 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - LBI NY General, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - LBI NY General, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - LBI NY General, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - LBI NY A-Z, 1981-1983 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - LBI NY General, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - LBI NY General, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - LBI NY Gruenewald, 1983-1986 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - LBI NY General, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - LBI NY Lessing and Schorch, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - LBI NY General, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - LBI NY General, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - LBI Executive, 1986-1989 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - LBI NY General, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - LBI NY General, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - LBI NY Various, 1990-1994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - LBI NY Saur/YB and Leipzig Meeting, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - LBI NY General, 1991-1993 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - LBI NY Meyer, 1991-1993 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - LBI Jerusalem/Tel Aviv, 1973-1986
      - LBI Jerusalem, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - LBI Jerusalem, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - LBI Jerusalem, 1979-1981 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - LBI Jerusalem, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - LBI Jerusalem, Dr. Moses, 1973-1978 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - LBI Tel Aviv, 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - LBI Tel Aviv, 1978-1981 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - LBI Tel Aviv, 1982-1986 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 3: Minutes, reports, and organizational documents, undated, 1955-1968; 0.3 linear feet.
    This subseries contains such internal reports, administrative documents, and meeting minutes as were found. However, this is most likely an incomplete collection of organizational documents.
    This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Accounts, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Aims and Organization of LBI, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1957-1963 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1966, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Frankfurt Jews Project Meeting Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Germania Judaica Programme, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - LBI Goals, undated, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Memoirs, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Work Report, 1966 August (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 4: Various, undated, 1957-1970s; 4 folders.
    This subseries contains a few miscellaneous folders and documents.
    - Book List, 1960? (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Gegenwart im Rueckblick Festschrift, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Notes, undated, 1960s-1970s (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Paucker research on Yiddish language, 1957-1962 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Presentations and talks, 1959-1965 (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Series IV: Printed Material, undated, 1923-2004; bulk 1955-1975; 2.2 linear feet.
  This series contains printed materials that were clipped and saved by LBI London. A wide range of publications is represented. Many clippings come from mainstream European (primarily German and English) newspapers and scholarly journals. The American press as well as the worldwide Jewish press are also well-represented.
  Additional printed material is found in the Yearbook and Schriftenreihe series, under Reviews.
  This series is divided into three subseries, each following original order. The first subseries contains reviews and commentaries on publications pertaining to German Jews. The second subseries contains clippings about LBI London. The third subseries consists of subject files created by LBI London.
  - Subseries 1: Reviews of German-Jewish publications, undated, 1955-1999; bulk 1957-1975; 0.8 linear feet.
    This subseries contains reviews of and commentaries on publications by LBI and its associated scholars, as well as other publications pertaining generally to German Jews. A wide range of publications is represented. Many clippings come from mainstream European (primarily German and English) newspapers and scholarly journals. The American press as well as the worldwide Jewish press are also well-represented.
    This series is arranged alphabetically by author's last name or by title.
    - Arendt, "Eichmann in Jerusalem", 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Arendt, "Eichmann in Jerusalem", 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Arendt, "Eichmann in Jerusalem", 1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Arendt, "Rahel Varnhagen", 1958-1960 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Auerbach, "Pionier der Verwirklichung", 1966-1970 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Bach, "Jacob Bernays", 1975 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Baeck, Leo, 1957-1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Baeck, Leo "Gedenkbuch", 1959-1961 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "Bewaehrung im Untergang", 1965 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Blumenfeld, "Erlebte Judenfrage", 1963-1977 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, "Was niemals stirbt", 1966-1968 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "Bulletin of the Leo Baeck Institute", 1958-1971 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - "Deutsches Judentum", 1963-1967 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - "Germania Judaica", 1963-1970 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Glatzer, "Leopold und Adelheid Zunz", 1958-1961 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Grunberger, "A Social History of the Third Reich", 1971 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Haavara", 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Handlin, "Jews in the Culture of Middle Europe", 1964 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Heymann, "Der Chevalier von Geldern", 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - "Hildesheimer Briefe", 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Hindls, "Einer kehrte zurueck", 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Hochhuth, "Der Stellvertreter", 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      Clippings very fragile
    - Kohn, "Martin Buber", 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Lazarus Gedenkbuch, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - LBI New York Catalog, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Lichtheim, "Rueckkehr", 1971 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - "Monatsschrift fuer Geschichte und Wissenschaft", 1966 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Moses, Festschrift, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Paucker, "Der juedische Abwehrkampf", 1968-1970 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Ruelf, "Stroeme in duerrem Land", 1965 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Stern, "Josel von Rosheim", 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Strauss, "Wir lebten in Deutschland", 1962 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Studies of the Leo Baeck Institute, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Susman, "Ich habe viel Leben erlebt", 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Tietz, "Geschichte einer Familie und Ihrer Warenhaeuser", 1965 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Wallach, "Liberty and Letters", 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Wandel, "Hans Schaeffer", 1975 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Weltsch, "An der Wende des modernen Judentums", 1972-1975 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Zondek, "Auf festem Fusse", 1974 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Various, 1955-1982 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Various, Undated, 1965-1971 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Various, 1984-1988 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Various, 1987-1989 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Various, 1995-1999 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Subseries 2: LBI London clippings, 1955-2004; bulk 1955-1975; 5 folders.
    This subseries contains clippings about LBI London. A wide range of publications is represented. Many clippings come from mainstream European (primarily German and English) newspapers and scholarly journals. The American press as well as the worldwide Jewish press are also well-represented.
    The original order inside these folders was maintained. The contents are in rough chronological order, and the folders are arranged by earliest date.
    - General clippings, 1955-1958 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - General clippings, 1956-1962 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - General clippings, 1962-1979 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - General clippings, 1970-1975 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - General clippings, 2002-2004 (Box 22, Folder 49)